[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
tricentis tasa Advanced
Training as you all know I've already
published 43 YouTube videos covering
beginners intermediate and advanced
level Concepts so in my previous video
on words I started teaching you some
realtime scenarios how can we automate
your test cases whenever you encounter
different types of obstacles while
automating your test cases by using
trient Tas this is our second
lesson pertaining to real time scenarios
in this lesson I'm going to teach you
how can we automate your test case when
you ENC cter an obstacle where you have
a duplicate elements with same
properties same multiple
properties so let us go back to our
Chrome browser let us
understand what is the obstacle that we
are going to solve for so we're going to
solve our second
obstacle which is automate a test step
that clicks on the button labeled I am
the one the second one on the right hand
side I can see I am the one I am the one
there are two buttons with the same name
so we have to click on the button which
is located on right
side for that let's go back to trient
Tason and here let us scan the
application
and the objects that are required to
automate so here let's right click on
obstacles folder click on scan and
select the
application so here is our application
let's select the application and click
on
scan so let me maximize this and if you
see here there are two buttons or two
links I am the one I am the one so we
are interested in these two buttons
let's check the properties of these two
buttons the first button on right side
which is using ID and
tag and ID is ID tag is a let's go back
to another button which has an ID
property as ID and tag as a value so
that means both the properties are same
and let's see what is the inner text it
says I am the one your inner HTML says I
am the one your inner text says I am the
one let's go back here so even this
button has same inner text and all other
properties are same so in this case how
can we
solve automating our test case so there
are two
methods so if I select this button here
now you can see this says your selected
item is not your so how can we make
these buttons as unique buttons there
are two ways the first one
is by using
index go to
identify and select
index so if you see here the first
button has an index of null and second
has an index of two if you see here the
selected item is not unique as soon as I
select this so now your button is
uniquely identified but I don't want to
use that method because what if in
future you introduce another button in
middle or somewhere right side then what
happens the index of this button becomes
three that means your test case is going
to
fa so what we can do there is another
method we can use the parent object to
identify this button for that we have to
expand the filter to see additional
objects let's go and expand here expand
some more but here if you see
this button is under I am the one and
this button is under I the one container
so basically this is one container and
this is another container let's see if
these containers are uniquely identified
if you select this container let's go
back to identify by
properties so here the container
pertaining to the first
button has
ID this
is this one is the right and let's see
the container pertaining to the other
button here this one this one
says the inner text is empty that means
these two containers are uniquely
identified the first button has an ID
this is the
right and this one has an IDE of
empty so that means I can
use the container parent container to
identify this particular button let us
select this parent container as soon as
I select so now it says you I am the one
button is uniquely identified see
whenever I remove this
here see this is not uniquely identified
if I select this container now your
object is uniquely
identified so now let us rename this
particular module as the obstacle
name copy and here rename this it is a
best practice to rename your modules in
a logical
way now let's save this particular
module and close
this let us go back to trient TOS so
this is our new obstacle module and here
I can see this button so now let me
create a new test case here right click
and create a test case name this as
abstract
1 129 Y2 and here let's double click on
this test case and I would like to drag
and drop this module onto the test
case and expand this so it is very easy
for us to automate this test case once
you solve the unique identification of
the object so here you can see it has a
container also and it has the button so
this particular button is under a
container called this
one and which is uniquely identified
right so here to click on this button I
would like to use again click which is
not recommended you need to use x but I
want to see the cursor so that I can
observe closely on which button we are
clicking by using this particular test
case
so now let us run this particular test
case and see if we can click on the
button which is on right
side see it is clicking on the button
which is right side good job you solve
this automation
problem so you can see the the test
result here your test result is
passed once you complete automating the
test case it's best practice to mark
this as completed and save
this hope you all understand how can we
solve the obstacle where two identical
objects having same
properties if you have any queries leave
your queries in the comment box I'll try
to respond respond to your
query oh you all understand how can we
solve our second obstacle whenever you
try to automate your test cases by using
triena where you have multiple objects
and both the objects has the same
properties please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell IC on you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos thank you
[Music]